BRIAN HUNGERMAN
CSE 15
---------------
HW-1
---------------
1.1, 10)
	d) q → p
	If the votes have been counted, the election has been decided;
	e) ¬q →¬p
	If the votes have not been counted, the election has not been decided;
	f) ¬p →¬ q
	If the election is not decided, then the votes have not been counted;
1.1, 12)
	c) q →¬ r 
	If you missed the final examination, you fail the course
	e) (p →¬r)∨(q →¬r)
	You either have the blue and fial the course or you miss the final examination and you fail the course
1.1, 22)
	a) If you wash the car's boss, then you will be promoted
	b) If there are winds from the south, then it implies a spring thaw
	c) If you bought the computer less than a year ago, then the warrenty is good
	d) If Willy cheats, then he gets caught
	e) If you pay a subscription fee, then you get access to the website
	g) If Carol is on a boat, then she gets seasick
1.2, 4) 
	"To use the wireless network in the airport you must pay the daily fee unless you are a subscriber to the service."
	w = (¬s→d) ∨ s
1.2, 16) 
	a) "Are you a liar?" to a liar makes him say "no". "Air you a liar?" to a truthful cannibal makes him say "no" as well. Thus you cannot deduce any conclusion.
	b) "Are you alive?" is a question where a liar would say no, but a truthful cannibal would say yes.
1.2, 36)
	a) If Carlos says Diana did it, and Diana says Carlos lied about that statement. To be logically consistent, one of them must be telling the truth. 
	   Therefore, John must be lying, which means he is guilty.
	b) In the same line of reasoning, either Diana or Carlos is lying. Therefore, Alice must be telling the truth. Carlos is guilty.
1.3, 10)
	a) [¬p∧(p∨q)]→q
		P	Q	RESULT
		T	T	T
		T	F	T
		F	T	T
		F	F	T
	b) [(p → q)∧(q → r)]→(p → r) 
		P	Q	R	RESULT
		T	T	T	T
		T	F	T	T
		F	T	T	T
		F	F	T	T
		T	T	F	T
		T	F	F	T
		F	T	F	T
		F	F	F	T
	c) [p∧(p → q)]→q		
		P	Q	RESULT
		T	T	T
		T	F	T
		F	T	T
		F	F	T
	Since the result is T for all cases, all three are tauntologies
1.3, 20) 
	Show that¬(p⊕q) and p ↔ q are logically equivalent.
	XOR is true if p and q are different. NOT XOR would imply p and q are the same value (either both T or both F)
	This coincides with the biconditional, which is also true with p and q are the same value (either both T or both F)
	
	
 